ALAN HENRY

FULL STACK DEVELOPER



EDUCATION

BEng (Hons) Automotive Engineering

University of Huddersfield 2002 - 2006

CERTIFICATIONS

NETWORK+

CompTIA Completed: March 2023

SKILLS

PROFESSIONAL

Communication Teamwork Attentive Pragmatic

TECHNICAL

Angular NodeJS HTML

CSS

MongoDB

SQL

Firebase

Azure

Docker

Python

Git & Github

Microsoft 365

Linux

Trello

Agile

PROFILE

Self-driven and analytical team player with 13 years of experience in the military. A diligent individual who thrives on problem-solving and getting the details right while delivering to time and target. Seeking opportunities to be at the forefront of advancements in IT. Excited about progressing in my career trajectory shift from the military to full stack developer with a focus on Angular based web applications.

EXPERIENCE

FULL STACK DEVELOPER

With You With Me | 2023 - Present

- Creating a secure, reactive Angular and MongoDB based online shop application with full CRUD capability for products, customer orders and customer details.
- The app is secured with OpenID Connect & OAuth and hosted on Microsoft Azure.

BRANCH INFORMATION TECHNOLOGY SECURITY OFFICER

British Army | 2021 - 2023

- Ensured continuous compliance with latest updates and backups, preventing the risk of data loss or theft.
- Maintained records of all workstations and personal electronic devices, ensuring accountability and enhancing overall security measures.

TEAM LEADER

British Army | 2010 - 2023

- Performed as part of a large multi-disciplinary team producing world-class ceremonial music for high-profile military, royal, and charity engagements globally.
- Successfully led and managed multiple teams on time-sensitive projects to achieve high standards of completion.
- Provided first-line incident response within the London Central Garrison to maintain vital security.
- Mentored, trained, and ensured welfare of new employees.

NEW PRODUCT DEVELOPMENT ENGINEER

Keighley Laboratories | 2008 - 2009

- Worked under own initiative to provide clients with customised product designs using Solidworks CAD software.
- Built business-to-business customer relations to increase the customer base.

RESEARCH ASSISTANT

University of Huddersfield | 2006 - 2007

- Designed and developed teaching resources through innovative integration of experimental facilities with computational resources.
- This provided students with the ability to run tests on automotive power units both in the labs and remotely using software simulations.

ADDITIONAL ACTIVITIES

- Army Mountain Bike Instructor
- Music composition and arrangement for professional ensembles
- Freelance musician